<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Muhammad's Blog</title><link>https://muhammad-blog.netlify.app/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Muhammad's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 14:27:24 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://muhammad-blog.netlify.app/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ASCII Art -Image to ASCII Converter-</title><link>https://muhammad-blog.netlify.app/posts/ascii-art-image-to-ascii-converter-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 14:27:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://muhammad-blog.netlify.app/posts/ascii-art-image-to-ascii-converter-/</guid><description>Introduction ASCII art is the forming pictures or art out of the ASCII&amp;rsquo;s printable characters.
input output ASCII art is used wherever text can be more readily printed or transmitted than graphics, or in some cases, where the transmission of pictures is not possible. This includes printers, old phones or even Google meet and twitch chat!
How it works In this article u will learn how to make a program that converts a given image to ASCII characters, using the C++ programming language and the SFML Multimedia libray.</description></item><item><title>Shellmates Welcome-day challenge BOT</title><link>https://muhammad-blog.netlify.app/posts/shellmates-welcome-day-challenge-bot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://muhammad-blog.netlify.app/posts/shellmates-welcome-day-challenge-bot/</guid><description>Every year, the clubs at our campus compete to promote their activities in order to attract newcomers. Each club innovates and tries its best to convince people to join it and get them familiarized with its workflow.
At Shellmates Club, we decided to make a challenge based on a discord bot, in which players can discover the field of Cyber Security and CTF&amp;rsquo;s. In addition to that, it will get them familiarized with our main working platform, discord.</description></item><item><title>Talentscrap</title><link>https://muhammad-blog.netlify.app/posts/talentscrap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://muhammad-blog.netlify.app/posts/talentscrap/</guid><description>Talentscrap is a web scrapping script i wrote using python and Selenium to extract data from ESI Talents public profiles.
Selenium is a great tool which is primarily used to automate web browsing interactions for testing purposes, but is certainly not limited to just that and can be used for exemple to scrap data.
Context I was following a course on databases architectures and SQL commands. It was a very good academic course by a professor at Stanford, it helped me getting the essential concepts, but i prefer the project based learning approach, that&amp;rsquo;s why I needed some data to create a database and practice what i learned on it.</description></item></channel></rss>